Hello everyone and welcome to English
Pod, my name is Marco and my name is
Katherine and today we're talking about
a very important day in a couple's life.
That's right, we're going to a wedding
and but this time it's not going to be so
romantic because actually the the groom is
having second thoughts about the wedding.
Okay that means he's nervous and he's
not positive he wants to get married today.
So remember the groom is
the man, the bride is the woman.
Let's jump right into this dialogue,
listen to what's going on and when we
come back we'll be talking about some
of the words and phrases you've heard.
Man, I'm freaking out. You gotta help me.
Whoa, whoa, take it easy, relax.
Jeez, you're sweating like a pig.
What's going on?
I can't go through with this. I just
can't. I'm not ready for marriage.
What was I thinking?
I'm only 35 years old.
I've got my entire life ahead
of me. Adventure's waiting.
I can't settle down yet.
What are you talking about?
It wasn't more than a month ago that you
were rambling on about how you are tired
of living the life of a bachelor and how
you envy your friends that have a family.
I know, I know. Let's think this through. First of
all, you cannot leave Amy at the altar. Not only
will she be humiliated and kill you, but she is the
woman that you love and the woman of your dreams.
Why would you want to end that or
jeopardize it like this? Second of all, you
were just getting cold feet. You know deep
down inside that you want to marry her.
So cut the crap and
do it. You're right.
I'm being crazy. Okay, I'm
ready. Let's do this. Great.
Whew, that was a close one. You
had me going there for a minute.
I thought I was going to have
to slap some sentence to you.
All right, we're back so
almost. He almost didn't get
married, but luckily you have
a good friend to help you out.
Exactly. So this friend really
saved the day, made sure that the
groom didn't get too nervous
and had some really positive words.
So let's take a listen to some of these
marriage words in today's language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
All right, so as you mentioned,
we have this word marriage.
Now marriage is the noun form, right, of
actually getting married or to be married.
Right. Marriage is the
noun, the word that describes
the relationship between
two married people.
Okay, and so you have a relationship,
maybe you're dating, but once you get
married, the thing between you as a
man and a woman, that's your marriage.
Your marriage.
You could say our marriage is in danger.
We need to work on our marriage. Exactly.
Or we have a happy marriage. All right.
Okay, so that's marriage.
Now if you get married, and
this guy, he mentioned a
phrase which was to settle down.
To settle down, this is a very
important phrase. To settle down
means to get serious, mature,
and to stop living like a child.
It means really to have a house or
to start having kids. It's a time in life.
So to settle down is to become more stable,
right, as you say, to buy a house, to
have a family, to stay in one place and
not be so adventurous or stuff like that.
Exactly. So it's to calm down
and to be more fixed in life.
All right. Now the opposite of
this would be to be a bachelor.
Right. So bachelor is a single
man, someone who's not married.
And you often hear this term
when we talk about apartments.
So bachelor pad is an apartment
that's specific to a single man.
Usually there's lots of video games
and fancy TV and a pool table, exactly.
All right. So bachelor, we had a
lesson about this called bachelor party.
Right. Which is a party for a
man right before he gets married.
Okay. And bachelor is a special
word for a man who's not yet married.
Okay. Very good. And now
as they were talking about not
getting married, he said that
he can't leave any at the altar.
So you often
hear this in movies.
She got left at the altar or
you can't leave her at the altar.
This word altar is
actually religious.
Altar is the table in a church
where the priest does all of his work.
Right. Right.
So an altar is a special religious table.
So usually two people will
stand in front of an altar and get
married right with the priest
who is doing his thing there.
He says do you Joe takes Samantha
to be your bride blah blah blah blah.
So that happens at a
special place called the altar.
Okay. Very good. It's also common
in the normal mass like on Sundays.
Right. Okay. And for the last word
or phrase today, it's to get cold feet.
You're just getting cold feet.
Okay. So this is a very
funny phrase in English
because it doesn't actually
mean that you're cold.
Right. So cold feet
means you're nervous
about something. You
might change your mind.
Okay.
So people often talk about men and
women getting cold feet before a wedding.
But you can also relate it to any other
situation, not only getting married, right?
Yeah. For example, I'm going to go
jump out of an airplane tomorrow. Okay.
Fast forward tomorrow.
Oh no. I have cold feet.
I don't think I want to
jump out of an airplane.
Okay. So that's
the good cold feet.
Second thoughts or doubts
about actually doing something.
Exactly. Cold feet.
All right. So why don't we
listen to our dialogue again?
Let's keep a lookout
for all of these words.
And we'll be back in a little bit.
Man, I'm freaking out.
You got to help me. Whoa.
Whoa. Take it easy. Relax. Geez. You're
sweating like a pig. What's going on?
I can't go through with this.
I just can't. I'm not ready for marriage.
What was I thinking? I'm only 35 years old.
I've got my entire
life ahead of me.
Adventures waiting. I
can't settle down yet.
What are you talking about?
It wasn't more than a month ago that you
were rambling on about how you are tired
of living the life of a bachelor and how
you envy your friends that have a family.
I know. I know. Let's think this through.
First of all, you cannot
leave Amy at the altar.
Not only will she be
humiliated and kill you,
but she is the woman that you
love and the woman of your dreams.
Why would you want to end
that or jeopardize it like this?
Second of all, you were
just getting cold feet.
You know, deep down inside
that you want to marry her.
So cut the crap and do it.
You're right. I'm being crazy.
Okay. I'm ready. Let's do this.
Great. That was a close one.
You had me going there for a minute.
I thought I was going to have
to slap some sense into you.
All right. We're back. So now why
don't we take a look at four key phrases
that we found in this
dialogue on fluency builder?
Fluency builder.
This first one is a really
great phrase because it's very,
well, it's easy to picture
this, what we're describing.
Sweating like a pig to sweat like a pig.
Okay. You're sweating like a pig.
All right. This is a, this is a way to
say that someone is sweating a lot.
A lot. Okay.
And it's really gross or disgusting.
Now do pigs actually sweat?
I don't know if pigs actually sweat,
but you imagine someone smells bad
and they have, you know, sweat on
their face and their back and their arms.
All right. Well, sometimes don't
you say you're sweating like a dog?
You could also say that.
I guess we like animals in English,
but this is just a really great way
to say that someone is really sweaty.
All right. And well, he was sweating
and he was really nervous because
he said, I can't go through with this.
What does he mean?
Go through with this with what?
To go through with means
to actually do something. Okay.
So maybe I say, I don't want
to jump out of an airplane.
I can't go through with this.
Okay. I can't jump.
So it depends on what
we're actually talking about.
Okay.
If we're talking about a wedding,
you say, I can't go through with this.
I can't get married.
So if you're planning a robbery,
you say, well, in the last minute,
I couldn't go through with it.
I backed out.
Right.
I can't complete what I talked about doing.
Okay. And now the friend, he finally gets
kind of angry and he says, cut the crap.
Oh, man. This is a
very common phrase.
All right. This is, this is someone
says this if they don't want to listen to
complain anymore. Okay.
Marco, cut the crap. Okay.
I don't want to hear your excuses.
I don't want to hear your complaints.
I want to just hear solutions,
solutions, ideas, positive things.
So it's a cut the crap
is no more complaints,
no more excuses, or no
more talking nonsense.
Exactly. And this is, this is common
among teachers and, well, parents.
All right. So cut the crap.
Now it's not very polite,
right? So you wouldn't
really say it to your boss
or not for like a friend.
Cut the crap is kind of rude.
And it's very spoken language.
So I wouldn't write it
down. And I would not
use this with someone
who is like a teacher.
Well, yeah, like an authority.
You don't use it with them.
They might use it with you. Okay.
And for our last phrase, he said, who
you had me going there for a while?
Or he had me going there for a minute.
Okay.
So this is a really interesting phrase.
We use this a lot in English,
but it's not clear from listening
to it what it might mean.
So you had me going
there in this sense
means, oh, I was really
nervous for a minute.
I really believed what you were saying.
Exactly. So maybe we could
give an example Marco. All right.
Did you know that
yesterday I won a lottery?
I mean, I won like a million dollars
and I had the perfect numbers.
Oh, my God. Really?
Can I have a million dollars?
I would love to help
you out, ma'am, but, yeah,
no, I didn't actually
win a million dollars.
You had me going there for a minute.
You actually did.
You believed me. You believed me.
Okay. Maybe not. He's not that. Go.
That's gullible. All right.
But that's what it means, right?
To believe someone's story or to
think that something's going to happen,
even though it doesn't,
you had me going there.
That means what you thought
was going to happen didn't happen.
So you can use it in the
third person is like, yeah,
I was telling him this awesome story
and I really had him going for a while.
He really believed me.
And then I told him it wasn't true.
Okay. Great phrases. Now let's
listen to our dialogue for the last time
and we'll be back to talk a little
bit more about getting cold feet.
Man, I'm freaking out. You got to help me.
Whoa. Whoa. Take it easy. Relax.
Jeez. You're sweating like a pig.
What's going on?
I can't go through with this.
I just can't. I'm not ready for marriage.
What was I thinking? I'm only 35 years old.
I've got my entire life ahead of me.
Adventure's waiting.
I can't settle down yet.
What are you talking about?
It wasn't more than a month ago that
you were rambling on about how you are
tired of living the
life of a bachelor and
how you envy your
friends that have a family.
I know. I know. Let's think this through.
First of all, you cannot
leave Amy at the altar.
Not only will she be
humiliated and kill you,
but she is the woman that you
love and the woman of your dreams.
Why would you want to end
that or jeopardize it like this?
Second of all, you were
just getting cold feet
deep down inside that
you want to marry her.
So cut the crap and do it. You're right.
I'm being crazy. Okay.
I'm ready. Let's do this.
Great. That was a close one.
You had me going there for a minute.
I thought I was going to have
to slap some sense into you.
All right.
So this is a popular scenario, right?
Somebody at Dom
and they're wedding day.
They get cold feet and
they, you know, they back out.
TV, movies, books,
everyone loves the situation.
Have you ever actually heard of or
experience or maybe known of somebody
who actually left the bride at
the altar or the groom at the altar?
I don't know anyone who did that locally.
I think it's really sad.
I mean, you know, I don't
think it's really that common.
Now, but there was a movie just about this.
So there's a woman
Julia Roberts who tries and
tries and tries to get
married but never can.
So it's called runaway bride because
every time she goes to the altar,
she gets nervous, she gets
cold feet and she runs away.
It's the call for
the runaway bride.
I can't imagine it's actually
happening to someone.
I mean, you have all your
family there, your friends.
You know, it'd be so embarrassing.
It's amazing and expensive.
Exactly because you've
already paid for everything.
So do you get to eat the cake if
you're the one who's left behind?
I don't think so.
Everything's paid for, right? Exactly.
You drink all the liquor. All right.
So that's all the time we have for
today. If you have any questions,
any comments you can come
to our website at EnglishPod.
com and we'll see you guys
there. Bye, everyone. Bye.